haikudeck.com 2019-12-24

# Presentation Software | Online Presentation Tools | Haiku Deck

This Privacy Policy is effective June 11, 2019.

* ### Accepting the Privacy Policy

We at Haiku Deck, Inc. ("Haiku Deck," "we," "us," "our”) know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. By accessing or using the Services (including without limitation the mobile version of the haikudeck.com website (the “Mobile Site”) and the Haiku Deck mobile application(s) (collectively, the “Mobile Application”), you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy and that you accept our Terms of Service. Remember that your use of Haiku Deck’s Services is at all times subject to the Terms of Service, which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use here without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service.

By using the Services, you acknowledge that Haiku Deck will use your information in the United States and any other country where Haiku Deck operates. Please be aware that the privacy laws and standards in certain countries, including the rights of authorities to access your personal information, may differ from those that apply in the country in which you reside. We will transfer personal information only to these countries to which we are permitted by law to transfer personal information, and we will take steps to ensure that your personal information continues to enjoy appropriate protections. Please read on to learn more about how we protect personal information that’s transferred outside of Europe.

We respect your privacy. Haiku Deck will not disclose your name, email address or other personal information to third parties without your consent, except as specified in this policy.

We use your information to provide and improve the Services and our products, for billing and payments, for identification and authentication, for targeted online and offline marketing including through tools like Facebook Custom Audience and Google Customer Match, to contact members or interested parties, and for general research and aggregate reporting.

* ### What does this privacy policy cover?

This Privacy Policy explains how Haiku Deck collects and uses information from its Service’s users, including our treatment of personally identifiable information. This policy does not apply to websites or practices of companies that Haiku Deck does not own or control, or to individuals that Haiku Deck does not employ or manage.

* ### Children's Personal Information

If you are not of legal age to form a binding contract (in many jurisdictions, this age is 18), you may only use the Services and disclose information to us with your parent’s or guardian’s express consent. Review this Privacy Policy with your parent or guardian and make sure you understand it, and do the same with the privacy policies of all websites you visit or mobile applications you use. Haiku Deck only collects personal information through the Services from a child under 13 where that student’s school, district, and/or teacher has agreed (via the terms described in more detail in the Terms of Service to obtain parental consent for that child to use the Services and disclose personal information to us, for the use and benefit of the learning environment. If you are a student under 13, please do not send any personal information about yourself to us if your school, district, and/or teacher has not obtained this prior consent from your parent or guardian, and please do not send any personal information other than what we request from you in connection with the Services. If we learn we have collected personal information from a student under 13 without parental consent being obtained by his or her school, district, and/or teacher, or if we learn a student under 13 has provided us personal information beyond what we request from him or her, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student under 13 may have provided us personal information in violation of this paragraph or if you are a parent wishing to request the deletion of student data, please contact us at [privacy@haikudeck.com.](mailto:privacy@haikudeck.com)

When we use the term "Personal Information" in this Privacy Policy, we are referring to personally identifiable information of individual, non-student registrants of the Services. References to "Children's Personal Information" only apply to personally identifiable information of users who have registered for the Services as minor students (i.e., students under the age of 18). General references to "information" apply to all users.

* ### Privacy Policy Updates

Due to the Internet's rapidly evolving nature, Haiku Deck may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, Haiku Deck will post our updated Privacy Policy two business days ahead of time on our Site located at www.haikudeck.com/privacy so you are always aware of what personally identifiable information we may collect and how we may use this information. Haiku Deck will also send registered users of the Site e-mail notifications notifying such users of any changes to the Privacy Policy. Haiku Deck encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of this Site and/or continued provision of personally identifiable information to us will be subject to and indicates your agreement with the terms of the then-current Privacy Policy.

* ### Information Collection

5.1 Information You Provide to Us

We receive and store any information you knowingly enter on the Services, whether via computer, mobile phone, other wireless device, or that you provide to us in any other way. This information may include, without limitation, Personal Information such as your name, user name, email address, phone number, profile picture, billing and payment information, and any other information necessary for us to provide our Services. You need to provide this information to enable us to provide you with the Services. You may review, change, or remove the name associated with your account any time through the account settings page.

Some members or visitors may choose to connect register a Haiku Deck account using an external third-party application, such as Facebook, Twitter, or Google. Haiku Deck may receive information from those connected third-party applications. Connecting your Haiku Deck account to third-party applications or services is optional. If you choose to connect your account to a third-party application, Haiku Deck may receive information from that application. We may also collect public information in order to connect with you. We may use that information as part of providing the Services to you. You can also choose to share some of your activity on Haiku Deck on certain social media networks which are connected to your Haiku Deck account, and you can revoke your permission anytime in your account settings.

If you are a student registrant, the only Children’s Personal Information we require is your user name; through the functionality of the Services, you may also be permitted to input a profile picture, an email address, or other information about yourself. In certain sections of this Site and when you download any software we may offer, we may invite you to contact us with questions or comments or request information, or you may be required to complete a profile or registration form. Due to the nature of some of these activities, we may collect personally identifiable information such as your name, e-mail address, password, organization and other contact information that you voluntarily transmit with your communication to us. You may edit or remove this information through your account settings page at www.haikudeck.com/account.

5.2 Information Collected Automatically

We may collect information about your use of the Services for advertising, analytics, to serve content, to provide customer service, and to protect the Services. This includes your IP address, browser information (including referrers), and device information. We receive and store certain types of usage information whenever you interact with the Services; this information is not Personal Information or Children's Personal Information. For example, Haiku Deck automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, Haiku Deck cookie information, and the page you requested. We also record the details of your activity on the Services, and the number and frequency of visitors to our site and its components.

When you download our Mobile Application, we automatically collect information on the type of device, name and version of the operating system, name and version of the application, user type, the numerical mobile device user ID, as well as actions performed by the user in accessing the Mobile Application (“Mobile Usage Information,” which is considered part of “usage information” as described above). However, we do not ask you for, access or track any geographic-location-based information from your mobile device (i.e., any information regarding where your mobile device is located on the globe at a particular time) at any time while using our Mobile Applications. For clarity, this does not prevent us from asking you what school or organization you are affiliated with.

We also use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Application and Mobile Site on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the Mobile Application, the events that occur within the Mobile Application, aggregated usage information, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from; this information is considered Mobile Usage Information.

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer or mobile device to enable our systems to recognize your computer or device and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people. Haiku Deck cookies do not collect Personal Information or Children's Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information or Children's Personal Information to tell us who you are or what your username or email address is. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. As critical functions of Haiku Deck rely upon cookies, authoring presentations via the web application and other elements of the web site will not function unless cookies are enabled.

* ### Information Use

6.1 Generally

When you use the Services, you may set up your personal profile, perform searches and queries, and transmit information through various channels and as permitted by the functionality of the Services. The information we gather from users enables us to personalize and improve our services, and allows users to set up a user account and profile through the Services.

6.2 Personal Information

The Personal Information you provide is used for such purposes as responding to your requests for certain information and services, customizing your experience, and communicating with you about the Services.

6.3 Children's Personal Information

We use the Children's Personal Information for creating your individual account (which will identify you within your classroom account), customizing your experience, and for sending you notifications via the Services from your teacher, school, district, fellow Classroom members, and from Haiku Deck (regarding your use of the Services) (“Notifications”). Data provided to Haiku Deck by students is retained for educational purposes.

6.4 Your email address

If you provide us your email address, we may send you email communications. Web beacons may also be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails (and which links within those emails) have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you are a student, we will only use your email address to send you Notifications. To opt out of receiving emails from us, please contact us at privacy@haikudeck.com. Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us via email, such as this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are responsible for visiting this Privacy Policy from time to time to review any changes.

6.5 Referral email addresses you explicitly provide

If you participate in an affiliate program and provide us with an email address of a referral, we will automatically send that referral an email inviting him or her to visit the Services. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this email (and, if applicable, subsequent “reminder” emails) and tracking the success of our referral program. The referred user may contact us at privacy@haikudeck.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

6.6 Usage Information

Haiku Deck uses this type of aggregate data to enable us to figure out how often users use parts of the Services, so that we can make the Services appealing and relevant to as many users as possible, and customize and improve those Services. We may link usage information to Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information that we collect through the Services, but we will only use this linked information internally (for example, to customize your experience). Additionally, certain usage-related information may be viewable in your user profile that may be displayed to other users, depending on your User Category; for example, a “badge” may displayed in your profile indicating that you have added presentations to your user “gallery.”

6.7 Mobile Usage Information

This information is used to determine the device capabilities and usage trends which allows us to better understand which devices we should support and what features are most frequently used.

6.8 Push Notifications

If you use the Mobile Application, we may occasionally send push notifications to your mobile device in order to make you aware of certain activities that may occur within your account. You may opt-out of receiving these types of communications by turning them off at the device level.

6.9 Agents

We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Examples include sending email, analyzing data, processing payment, and providing user services. Unless we tell you differently, Haiku Deck's agents do not have any right to use personal information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.

6.10 User Profiles

You may choose to populate your user profile on the Services with Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, including, without limitation, your name, photograph, and social media profiles. This user profile information will be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services or facilitate interaction with Haiku Deck. Please keep in mind that information (whether Personal Information or Children's Personal Information or not) or content that you voluntarily disclose online can become available to other users and can be collected and used by others, in accordance with the privacy settings you select in your account and presentation preferences. Any images, captions or other content that you submit to the Services in a manner any other user can view may be redistributed through the Internet and other media channels. For example, if you create a presentation with personal photos and information about yourself, this may be displayed to other users on the site if you do not adjust the privacy settings accordingly. Communication About the Services or in Response to User Requests

As part of the Services, you may receive from Haiku Deck email or other types of communication relating to your use of the Services or your user profile. You acknowledge and agree that by posting information on the Services or otherwise using the Services, Haiku Deck and its agents may send you email, contact you or engage in other communication that they determine relate to your profile or use of the Services. If you disclose your email address to Haiku Deck, we may use it to send updates, a newsletter or other news regarding the Services, or to simply send Notifications.

* ### Choice and Control

We know that members of our community value having control over their own information, so Haiku Deck gives you the choice of providing, editing or removing certain information, as well as choices about how we contact you. You may change or correct your Haiku Deck account information through your account settings. You may also remove certain optional information that you no longer wish to be publicly visible through the Services, such as your name. You can also request the deletion of the personal information in your account.

Depending on your location, you may also have certain additional rights with respect to your information, such as: (i) data access and portability (including the right to obtain a copy of your personal data you provided to Haiku Deck, via your settings); (ii) data correction (including the ability to update your personal data, in many cases via settings); (iii) data deletion (including the right to have Haiku Deck delete your personal information, except information we are required to retain, by contacting us); and (iv) withdrawal of consent or objection to processing (including, in limited circumstances, the right to ask Haiku Deck to stop processing your personal data, with some exceptions, by contacting us).

You may also control the receipt of certain types of communications from Haiku Deck in your account settings. Haiku Deck may send you messages about the Services or your activity. Some of these messages are required, service-related messages for subscribers (such as transactional messages or legal notices). Other messages are not required, such as newsletters. You can control which optional messages you choose to receive by changing your account settings, clicking the unsubscribe link in email messages, or by contacting us at team@haikudeck.com.

We may partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you have chosen to connect your account to an external third-party application, such as Facebook, you can change your settings and remove permission for the app by changing your account settings.

If you no longer wish to use the Services or receive service-related messages (except for legally required notices), then you may close your account. Click here to learn how to close your account.

On occasion, Haiku Deck may need to contact you. Primarily, these messages are delivered by email or by push notifications. In rare occasions, when requested, Haiku Deck may also contact you by telephone to provide member support or for transaction-related purposes. Additionally, Haiku Deck may send you an SMS (or similar) message or physical mail in order to provide you with customer support or to provide you with information about products and features that you may find of interest. You may update your contact preferences in your account settings.

Some messages from Haiku Deck are service-related and necessary for members and Guest Checkout users. You agree that Haiku Deck can send you non-marketing emails or messages, such as those related to transactions, your account, security, or product changes. Examples of service-related messages include an email address confirmation/welcome email when you register your account, key feature updates, and correspondence with Haiku Deck’s support team.

When you register for an account or provide us with your email address or phone number, you receive notice of and agree (in some jurisdictions and situations, by an additional unambiguous consent) to receive marketing emails and messages from us. You can unsubscribe at any time from marketing emails through the opt-out link included in marketing emails or messages. Members may also control some marketing emails or messages through their account settings as well as through the opt-out link included in marketing emails or messages.

* ### Business Transfers

If Haiku Deck, or some all of its assets were acquired or otherwise transferred, or in the unlikely event that Haiku Deck goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information may be transferred to or acquired by a third party. Such transactions or events may be necessary and in our legitimate interests, particularly our interest in making decisions that enable our business to develop over the long term. In these types of transactions (such as a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership, or transfer of all or substantially all of Haiku Deck’s assets), member information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. If Haiku Deck intends to transfer information about you, Haiku Deck will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the Site and the App, and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt out before information about you becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

* ### Protection of Haiku Deck and Others

We may release Personal Information or Children's Personal Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with the law (such as to comply with a subpoena); enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Haiku Deck, our employees, our users, or others. We will try to give you notice if we release information for these reasons, but please understand that we reserve the right not to, as it may not be practical, legal, or safe to do so.

* ### Links to Third Party Sites

The Site may provide links to other Web sites or resources over which Haiku Deck does not have control ("External Web Sites"). Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Haiku Deck of those External Web Sites. You acknowledge that Haiku Deck is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that Haiku Deck is not responsible for the content of such External Web Sites. Your use of External Web Sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies located on the linked to External Web Sites.

* ### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. Your account information is protected by a password. It is important that you protect against unauthorized access to your account and information by choosing your password carefully and by keeping your password and computer secure, such as by signing out after using the Services.

To protect your security, we may employ procedural and technological measures, consistent with industry practice. Such measures are reasonably designed to help protect your personally identifiable information from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Haiku Deck may use encryption, secure socket layer and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at privacy@haikudeck.com.

* ### Updating Personally Identifiable Information

Haiku Deck provides you with the ability to review and update the registration information that you provide to us by accessing and modifying this information on your user profile page. If a parent or guardian would like to request that Children’s Personal Information regarding their child be updated or deleted, or if you’d like to refuse further contact of your child (or, if you are a teacher, a child that is in your class) by the Services, please contact us at privacy@haikudeck.com. A minor student’s participation in our Services, and the ability of a minor student to access the Services, will not be conditioned on that student providing more Children’s Personal Information than is reasonably necessary for that participation or access. We will respond to a request made pursuant to this section within 30 days of our receipt of such request.

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to privacy@haikudeck.com.

* ### Retention

We will retain your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as long as needed to provide you the Services; we also may retain and use your information as we deem it necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements. If you no longer want Haiku Deck to use your information to provide the Services to you, you may close your account. [Click here](https://haikudeck.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/202230533-Delete-Close-Your-Haiku-Deck-Account) to learn how to close your account.

* ### Your Rights

You may benefit from a number of rights in relation to your information that we process. Some rights apply only in certain limited cases, depending on your location. If you would like to manage, change, limit, or delete your personal information, you can do so via your Haiku Deck account settings or by contacting us. Upon request, Haiku Deck will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. By visiting your account settings, you can access, correct, change, and delete certain personal information associated with your account. In certain cases where we process your information, you may also have a right to restrict or limit the ways in which we use your personal information. In certain circumstances, you also have the right to request the deletion of your personal information, and to obtain a copy of your personal information in an easily accessible format. Please ensure you've read the options you have under the "Choice & Control" section above. If you need further assistance, you can contact Haiku Deck through one of the channels listed below under “Contact.” We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

If we process your information based on our legitimate interests as explained above, or in the public interest, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons. Where we use your data for direct marketing purposes, you can always object using the unsubscribe link in such communications or changing your account settings.

* ### Withdrawing Consent

Where you have provided your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information and your use of the Services. For example, you can withdraw your consent to email marketing by using the unsubscribe link in such communications or by changing your account settings. You can choose to withdraw your consent to our processing of your information and your use of the Services at any time by closing your account through your account settings and then emailing privacy@haikudeck.com to request that your personal information be deleted, except for information that we are required to retain. This deletion is permanent and your account cannot be reinstated.

* ### Visitors from outside of the United States of America

When you use the Services, you are consenting to have your data transferred to and processed in the United States. All of Haiku Deck’s servers are currently in the United States, and we aren’t able to process your information within the borders of any other country. Given this limitation, if your use of the Services or disclosure of certain information to Haiku Deck would violate any law that is applicable to you, your right to use the Services and/or disclose such information is revoked, as it is wherever use of the Services is prohibited by law (as described in the Terms of Service). If you create a user account with the Site as a visitor from outside the United States, by using the Site you agree to this Privacy Policy and you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States, which may not offer an equivalent level of protection of that required in the European Union or certain other countries, and to the processing of that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Haiku Deck commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us via email at [privacy@haikudeck.com](mailto:privacy@haikudeck.com).

* ### General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a European privacy law that went into effect May 25, 2018, that governs the way companies collect, store, and share individuals' personal data. It was designed to give European citizens more control over such data. The following information is intended to provide information about Haiku Deck's compliance with GDPR and serve as a supplement to Haiku Deck's privacy policy.

#### What personal data does Haiku Deck collect?

We receive personal data from customers when they provide it voluntarily. These include:

  * Full name
  * Email address
  * Username
  * Password
  * Mailing address
  * Customer credit/debit token. Customer credit/debit information is stored by our third-party payment processor. Haiku Deck does not store credit/debit information.
  * User-generated content. We store presentation decks that users create through our web and mobile apps.

We also receive personal information from our service providers, including the following:

  * IP address
  * Web browser and device information
  * Page view information
  * Location information
  * Transaction amounts, dates, and times

If you use Facebook to access your Haiku Deck account or if you share content through Facebook or another third-party service, the third-party may share personal information with us. This will depend on the third-party's policies and your account settings with the third-party.

#### How do we store and manage your personal data?

We use cookies to help identify the way users navigate our website.

We collect and store personal data in order to effectively deliver and improve Haiku Deck services for our customers. We use personal data in the following ways:

  * Create and manage user profiles
  * Fulfill user requests
  * Answer user' questions
  * Providing assistance with our services
  * Comply with legal obligations

#### What security measures does Haiku Deck have in place?

We adhere to industry standard security policies and procedures designed to protect your personal data. We use encrypting technology (TLS) to ensure that your data is secure.

Access to portions of our site containing personal information is password protected. Personal data is backed up frequently such that we can ensure prompt access to personal data.

#### What rights do I have regarding my personal data?

You have the right to access, correct, and erase your personal data:

 **Access:  **You can request more information about what the data we store and manage, and we can provide you a record of such personal data.

 **Correction:  **If you believe any part of our record of your personal data is incomplete or inaccurate, you can request that we promptly correct it.

 **Erasure:  **You can request that we delete all of your personal information such that it is irretrievable.

 **Portability:  **You can request a copy of your personal data.

#### How can I remove my personal data?

You have a right to have your personal data deleted permanently from our system. To do so, please contact us at [support@haikudeck.com](mailto:support@haikudeck.com). We will remove your personal data promptly and irrevocably.

#### How can I access my personal data?

Besides access through the website and mobile apps, upon request, we will provide users with a record of all personal data associated with their Haiku Deck account. Users can make this request by contacting us at [support@haikudeck.com](mailto:support@haikudeck.com).

* ### Contact

If you have questions contact Haiku Deck’s support team via our [Support Site](https://haikudeck.zendesk.com/hc/en-us) or by emailing us at [privacy@haikudeck.com](mailto:privacy@haikudeck.com). You may also write to us at Haiku Deck, 999 3rd Ave. Suite 700, Seattle, WA 98104, USA.
